<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Yee Fan</title>
    <link>https://yeefantan.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://yeefantan.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://yeefantan.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://yeefantan.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My PhD Application</title>
      <link>https://yeefantan.github.io/post/my_journey_to_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yeefantan.github.io/post/my_journey_to_phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there! This post is written to share my experience of getting a Ph.D. position at Monash University Malaysia. I hope this post helps! Basically, I graduated with first-class honors (3.97/4.0) from Multimedia University (MMU). Also, I have decided to undertake a research degree since the 2nd year of my study. Hence, I have involved myself in different research projects to gain experience. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t share the entry requirements here, as this varies depending on the school. I will only be sharing my background and experience based on the application processes and interviews I encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself very fortunate to have three papers published while applying for the research degree. I have two experimental papers and one review article published during my undergraduate time. All of the published papers are in Q2. I believe having research experience is the most important factor. Hence, if you are still in your early stage of the undergraduate program and considering undertaking a research degree, you can try to contact any lecturer and ask if they have positions for a research assistant. Also, this will help you to gain strong recommendation letters. These letters could be significant in affecting the application outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-title-consideration&#34;&gt;Research Title Consideration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would suggest carefully considering your research title before getting engaged with a potential supervisor. This will really help to motivate you to dive deeper into the topic. And you will definitely enjoy the study! Do read and survey on the area you want to focus on, and slowly you will develop concrete ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;talk-to-a-potential-supervisor&#34;&gt;Talk to a potential supervisor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have decided on your research area, do reach out to the potential supervisor at the school. Positively, they will reply to your inquiries. I am very fortunate to have met the current supervisor, who is helpful, friendly, and supportive! Please get in touch with them as early as possible, and you may ask for a discussion, like an informal interview, to get to know each other better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your supervisor has agreed to supervise you, you may submit the application! Get all the documents ready and apply through the respective portal of the school. All you need to do is be patient and wait for the outcome! All the best and good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scholarship-interview&#34;&gt;Scholarship Interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, your school will have a separate round of scholarship interviews. I was nervous, indeed. Couldn’t give much suggestion on this. Familiarize yourself with your research area and strengths, and get prepared with some common scholarship/Ph.D. interview questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-words&#34;&gt;Extra words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could consider a direct Ph.D. entry if you hold a first-class honor in many countries (Malaysia/UK/Ireland etc). I also applied to some schools in the UK and Ireland and received interview invitations. I chose to stay in Malaysia as I think I have a pretty good research interest match with my current supervisor. I believe past research experience would be important for you to understand the topic better, find a potential supervisor, and secure your position at a school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand applying for a research degree could be stressful, and I was very worried back then. I have waited for approximately four to five months to receive the offer letter. Advice: Just work on things that can strengthen your profile while waiting for the result. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
